Guide to the WCSU Office of University Publications & Design Records RG 7.3.2 RG 7.3.2
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Office of University Publications & Design Records
1964-2014, (Bulk 1988-2000)
1988-2000
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Western Connecticut State University. Department of Academic Affairs.
Western Connecticut State University. Office of University Publications & Design.
Stewart, Peggy
RG 7.3.2
136
116 Linear Feet 125 boxes
The University Publications and Design Department is responsible for the production of academic publications and promotional materials for the university. The bulk of this collection consists of the working files for Diane Golden, Director of UP&D, from 1988 to 2000.
Provenance
Departmental transfer.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
In 2004, the University Publications & Design Department and the Office of Public Relations were brought together to become the Office of University Relations, which is now largely responsible for overall production of marketing materials for WCSU.
Scope and Content Note
The University Publications and Design Department is responsible for the production of academic publications and promotional materials for the university. Their services include design, copywriting, editing and photography for newsletters, billboards, advertisements, reports, magazines, viewbooks, postcards, posters, brochures and more. They also produce printed material for annual events such as Honors Convocations, Commencements and the University Ball.
The bulk of this collection consists of the working files for Diane Golden, Director of UP&D, from 1988 to 2000. They consist mainly of original art and mechanicals for publications that are generated from the department. View books, course catalogs, registration booklets, Annual Reports, The Western Way, Faculty Guidelines, and Commencement and Honors Convocation invitations and programs have been removed from this collection and filed within the existing University Archives collections.
Of special interest are the files for Opening, an independent magazine which was affiliated with WCSU. The monthly magazine previewed professional level arts in the Greater Fairfield County area. Among the founders were WCSU faculty members Lionel C. Bascom, John P. Briggs, Edward Hagan, Albert C. Stewart, Diane Golden, Abe Echevarria, Howard Tuvelle, and Hugh McCarney. The files contain correspondence, history of the tabloid, the premier issue of Opening ( spring 1990), information on printing specs, stationery and photographs.
Series XIII contains photographs from the late 1980s up to the 2000s.
Series XIV is the the University Photographer's (Peggy Stewart) archive which spans the years 1997-2014. There is overlap with materials in Series XIII and with RG8 WCSU Photographs and Miscellanea. The materials in series XIV began being accessioned in the summer of 2017.
Arrangement
The files are grouped into 14 series.
Photographs.; Handbooks.; Clippings.; Posters; Fliers (printed matter); Artists' proofs.; Illustrations.; Universities and colleges -- Administration.; Correspondence.; Universities and colleges -- Public relations.; Golden, Diane.; Stewart, Peggy; Western Connecticut State University. Office of University Publications & Design.
- Academics
  - General
    - Fliers and Events, Library, 1984-2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General
      Includes, bookplates, bookmarks, Fliers, and brochures
    - Brochures, Western @ Waterbury, 2000-2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Includes brochures for classes at Waterbury, brochures for events in Waterbury, registration postcards, and promotional pocket folder
    - Original artwork and mechanicals, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2.1)
      Includes Connecticut Association of Colleges and Universities in Teacher education stationary, International Center stationary, Women's History Project stationary, Berkshire Society logos, and general WCSU stationary
    - Graduate, Continuing Education and Honors Program Fliers, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 2.2)
      Includes The learning center, energey workshops, summer seminars, Western after 5, center for development studies, and graduate studies & extension services. Also includes the 3rd annual collegiate honors conference.
  - Ancell
    - Ancell Original Artwork and Mechanicals - School of business brochures, 1980s (Box OS 10, Folder 6)
    - Ancell Brochures and Fliers, 1970s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Includes MIS, JLA, MHA
    - Ancell Logos, 1990-2000s (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Includes Masters of Business Administration, Masters of Health Administration, Center for Business Research, Ancell Alumni Association, General Ancell Logos
    - Ancell - JLA Logo and Mechanicals, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4.1)
    - Ancell Invitations, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes 1998 reception and open house for graduates, a christmas card
    - Ancell Publications, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Economic Trends
    - Ancell Programs and events, 1982-2010 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Includes ads, fliers for slecture series, conferences, etc
  - Arts and Science
    - A&S Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Chemistry brochure, 1990s (Box OS 10, Folder 1)
    - A&S Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Dax Newsletter, Meteorology, Weather Center, 1990s (Box OS 10, Folder 2)
    - A&S Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Biology Dept. and Biology alumni, 1980s (Box OS 10, Folder 3)
    - A&S Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Biology brochure, and marine biology in jamaica brochure, 1988-1991 (Box OS 10, Folder 4)
      Includes Northeast Algal symposium
    - A&S Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Psychology Program, 1980s (Box OS 10, Folder 5)
      Includes Psychology of men brochure
    - A&S Brochures, 1979-2000s (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
      Includes brochures and fliers for the school of arts and science, the biology program, the chemistry program, the computer science program, the meteorology program, science and math enrichment program, and the social science program
    - A&S Logos & Mechanicals, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Includes mechanicals for the observatory, center for collaboration, science and mathematics enrichment program, a mock-up of a biology brochure, and the English society.
    - A&S Programs & Events, 1992-2009 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Includes brochures and fliers for the new age of exploration conference, physics placement testing, poetry readings, mathematical association fall meeting, anthropology conference, and Jane Goodall lecture
    - A&S Publications, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      DAX newsletter
  - Professional Studies
    - Prof Studies - Brochures & Fliers, 1979-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Includes brochures and fliers for the nursing program, school of professional studies, business workshop, health education, seminars for teachers, and social work
    - Prof Studies - Logos & Mechanicals, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Includes materials for the international center, social work, and nursing
    - Prof Studies Programs & Events, 1999-2008 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Includes future teachers of Connecticut conference brochure
  - Visual and Performing Arts
    - General
      - VPA Programs, 1980-2010 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        Includes brochures and fliers for West Stage, school of visual and performing arts, graphic design program, and art program
      - VPA Artwork and Mechanicals, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 17)
        Includes materials for graphic arts, pops concert, brass concert, arts festival, a view from the bridge play program, peanuts musical program, my man cabaret tribute, women writers event, senior illustration show, portfolio show, cupola artwork
      - VPA Calendars, 1980s-1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        Includes arts festival and locus
      - VPA Opening Magazine, History, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 29)
        Includes, newspaper articles, biographical blurb, intended scope of the project, staff with bios, advertisers, and subscription form
      - VPA Opening Magazine, Photographs, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
        Includes black and white photographs of Maureen Britt, M. Stuart Merritt, Robert Arneson, Ives Concert Pavillion, Greg Vegas, Margaret Grimes, Skitch Henderson, The Manhattan String Quartet,and Howard Tuvelle
      - VPA Opening Magazine, Misc. Photographs, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
        Includes black and white photographs used for advertisements in the premier issue
      - VPA Opening Magazine, Premier Issues, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
        Vol.1 No.1 1989 and Spring 1990 issues
      - VPA Opening Magazine, Printing Specs, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 33)
        Includes biographical blurbs, layout mechanicals, directives to printer, and schedule of advertising fees
      - VPA Opening Magazine, Stationary, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
        Includes address cards and letter stationary
      - VPA Opening Magazine, Premier Issue, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
        Draft with editorial notes of premier issue
      - VPA Opening Magazine, Misc., 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 36)
        Includes, advertisement from premier issue, faculty sbscription appeal, photocopies of sample art, and schedule of advertising fees
      - VPA Original Artwork & Mechanicals - outreach, 1989-1990 (Box OS 11)
        Includes original artwork and design for Opening that also include publication proofs, media kit, original art work and mechanicals.
      - VPA Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Misc., 1981-1988 (Box OS 14, Folder 3)
        Includes Artline
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals- Music and Summer Art Programs, 1990s (Box OS 14, Folder 4)
    - Music
      - Music Mechanicals, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 21)
        Includes program fliers, stationary, etc
      - Music Events, Jazz Festival, 2000-2009 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        programs from WCSU Jazz festivals
      - Music, Brochures anf Fliers, 1989-2010 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
        Includes, fliers and brochures
      - Music Events, General, 1964-2009 (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
        Includes programs and fliers for fall concerts, Yvgeny Yevtushenko, Howard Tuvelle, Anderson Quartet, Concert Choir, Ives Center, Symphonic Band, Symphony Orchestra, international music festival, summer music camp, flute camp, and string camp
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Faculty Recitals, 1985-1987 (Box OS 13, Folder 7)
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Center for Summer Jazz, 1988-1989 (Box OS 13, Folder 8)
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Concerts, 1981-2000 (Box OS 13, Folder 9)
      - Jazzfest Posters, 1996-2007 (Box OS 2, Folder 4)
      - Musical Performance Posters, 1990s-2000s (Box OS 2, Folder 8)
    - Theater
      - Theatre Events, 1983-2010 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        Includes opera and play programs for Carmen, Little Shop of Horrors, Anyone Can Whistle, A View from the Bridge, Death of a Salesman, How to Succeed in Business Without REally Trying, Picasso at the Lapin Agile, the Imaginary Invalid, and Kiss me Kate
      - VPA Original Artwork & Mechanicals - events, 1981-2000 (Box OS 12)
        Contains original artwork and mechanicals for theatrical posters as follows: A Bright Room Called Day; A Chorus Line; All My Sons; A Midsummer Night's Dream w/program; Androcles and the Lion; Antigone; Anyone Can Whistle; Arnold; A Streetcar Named Desire; Brighton Beach Memoirs; Broadway Bound; The Boys Next Door; Cat on a Hot Tin Roof; The Cherry Orchard; Death of a Salesman (1992); Equus; Fiddler on the Roof; Frankie and Johnny in the Clair de Lune; The Front Page (1993); Grease, Guys & Dolls; Hair; Hay Fever; Little Shop of Horrors; Man of La Mancha; Marathon '33; Merchant of Venice; Moliere Tartuffe; My Fair Lady; The Odd Couple; Oh What A Lovely War; The 3 Penny Opera; Pippin; Scapino; Stragglers in the Dust; 3 by Three; Uncommon Women and Others; Under Milk Wood; View from the Bridge; We Bombed in New Haven; Women Behind Bars; With or Without a Song.
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Weststage, 1980s (Box OS 13, Folder 6)
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals- Dance Festival, 1980s (Box OS 14, Folder 5)
      - Theatrical Posters, 1980s-2000s (Box OS 2, Folder 3)
      - Theatrical Posters Mounted, 1990s-2000s (Box OS 6, Folder 9-Jan)
    - Visual Art
      - Art Mechanicals, Alberetti Exhibit, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        Mechanicals for Bob Alberetti show invitation
      - Art Mechanicals, Art Awards, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Art Events, 1975-2009 (Box 1, Folder 27)
        Includes programs, fliers, and brochures for CARTUS Corp exhibition, student exhibitions, student portfolio shows, arts festivals, and faculty exhibitions
      - Original Artwork & Mechanicals, 1998 (Box OS 1)
        Contains photographs, some of which are mounted, and one folder marked b/w photos campus) Bill Quinnell's students, fall '98.
      - Mechanicals and Original Artwork - Portfolio Shows, 1984-1987 (Box OS 13, Folder 4)
      - Mechanicals and Original Artwork - Joyce Neufeld, undated (Box OS 13, Folder 5)
      - Original Artwork - Student Exhibitions, 1980s (Box OS 13, Folder 3-Jan)
        Contains original artwork and mechanicals for art exhibitions and shows and dance as follows: Graphic Art Exhibitions and Symposiums; Ceramics, Woodcuts and Engraving; Portfolio Shows; Student Exhibitions: Painting, Print Making, Drawing & Painting; Graphic art; Design; Color & Design; Typography; Music and Summer Art, and dance.
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Arts Festival, 1981-1982 (Box OS 14, Folder 1)
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - "Light Images," Exhibit of Contemporary Photography, 1985-1986 (Box OS 14, Folder 2)
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Art Symposium, 1988 (Box OS 14, Folder 3.1)
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Plonia Nixon, 1983 (Box OS 14, Folder 3.2)
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals -Grapic Design woodcut ceramics class, 1980s (Box OS 14, Folder 3.3)
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Two Abstract Paintings, undated (Box OS 14, Folder 6)
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Arts Festival Poster, 1976 (Box OS 14, Folder 7)
      - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Abstract Composition by Robert Alberetti, 1985 (Box OS 14, Folder 8)
        2 pieces
      - Misc. One 24" x 30" copy (sail boat), undated (Folder OS Folder 1)
        Print of painting "Jerry Jimmy" - use unknown.
- Administration
  - Athletics
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Football and baseball brochures, 1987-1991 (Box OS 10, Folder 12)
    - Brochures, and fliers, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Includes athletics program brochure, and coaching flier
    - Media Guides, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Includes women's soccer, football, and women's basketball
    - Events, 2003-2009 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Includes Awards banquet programs
    - Programs, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Includes women's basketball senior day, and men's basketball senior day
    - Programs, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      Includes football senior day
    - Programs, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Includes football, men's soccer, women's basketball, women's tennis, women's volleyball, and field hockey
    - Programs, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      Includes football, men's soccer, men's basketball, field hockey, volleyball, women's soccer, and women's basketball
    - Programs, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Includes men's soccer, women's tennis, and field hockey
    - Programs, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      Includes baseball, women's lacrosse, and softball
  - Events
    - Event Posters, 1990s-2000s (Box OS 2, Folder 2)
      Includes Presidents Lecture Series, Connecticut Student Poets, Danbury Actors Reperatory Theater, Bill Clinton returns to Westconn, Conflict Resolution, RA Outreach (Do you Stand Out in a Crowd?), Astronomy,
    - Event Posters, 1990s-2000s (Box OS 2, Folder 5)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - James Joyce, circa 2000 (Box OS 5, Folder 1)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Virginia Wolfe, 1992 (Box OS 5, Folder 2)
    - Events, Diversity/Multicultural Affairs, 1997-2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Including African American Film Festival, Women's History Month Events,
  - General Outreach
    - Fundraising - Cabaret Posters, 1990s-2000s (Box OS 2, Folder 7)
    - Original Artwork & Mechanicals - Misc, 1976-1990 (Box OS 3)
      Contains clip art, logos, and mastheads for campus publications
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Alumni Association, 1984 (Box OS 4, Folder 1)
    - Admissions - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Spring Registration, 1984-1991 (Box OS 4, Folder 2)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Registration booklets, 1988-1991 (Box OS 4, Folder 3)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Registration booklets, 1991-1993 (Box OS 4, Folder 4)
      Includes graduate, evening, and undergraduate 1993; graduate and continuing education 1991
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Registration, division of extended programs and Career Development, 1983-1984 (Box OS 4, Folder 5)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Homecoming, 1990-1999 (Box OS 4, Folder 6-7)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Miscellaneous artwork, undated (Box OS 5, Folder 3-5)
      Includes 2 pieces by Hildegard Woodward, and one R.C. Matteson print; Galloway Poetry mechanicals
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Honors, Open house, and produce room, 1980s (Box OS 7, Folder 1)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Pine Cone and Tree, 1980s (Box OS 7, Folder 2)
      Logo for Cinema IV, a.k.a Bantam Cinema
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Figure in cap and gown, 1980s (Box OS 7, Folder 3)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Anniversary Celebration, 1988 (Box OS 7, Folder 4)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Admissions artwork, nature themed, 1990 (Box OS 7, Folder 5)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Black History Month, 1995 (Box OS 7, Folder 6)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Misc. Calendars, 1990s (Box OS 7, Folder 7)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Financial planning seminar and orientation bulletin, 1989-1990 (Box OS 7, Folder 8)
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Buildings and Grounds, 1980s-1990s (Box OS 7, Folder 9-17)
      Includes Fairfield Hall, Old Main, White Hall, Haas Library, Campus map, WCSU beautification project
    - Original Artwork and Mechanicals - Misc. Events brochures, 1980s-1990s (Box OS 7, Folder 18)
      Includes a voice of her own: conference on women and writing; shoah; gus kalogeras party; president's holiday party; religion in the public schools; religion and the schools in a plural society; energy workshop; and 6th annual CT baccalaureate student conference
    - Original Artwork by Sam Maladouangdork., ca.1995 (Box OS 8)
      Five pen and ink sketches. (Westside entrance, Ancell Building, Haas Library, Fairfield Hall, anchored inboard cruiser) One watercolor portrait, artist unknown.
    - Original Artwork & Mechanicals - Danbury Community, 1981-2003 (Box OS 9)
      Contains original artwork and mechanicals for the following: Pen and ink aerial map of Midtown and Westside ca.1990; tree print; pinecones; pen & ink figure in cap and gown; Museum Mile NYC; "Biology Dept."; Black and white still life; Ancell School of Business; Psychology Program Undergraduate; and, one mounted Centennial "Special Thank To:" poster. Also contains original artwork and mechanicals for the City of Danbury and State of Connecticut as follows: Tarrywile Mansion Designers' Show House, Danbury Cultural Commission, Danbury Preservation Trust's Sunderland Award, Connecticut Youth Services, and, The Women's Center.
    - Multicultural Diversity Events Posters, 1990s-2000 (Box OS 2, Folder 1)
    - Mechanicals, Administration, 1989-1996 (Box 1, Folder 37-38)
      Includes Ives Center, Maps, degree offerings, general university graphics, summer programs, golf tournament, open house, enrollment, Includes open house, degree offerings, summer programs, general university graphics, open house, and evening program
    - Mechanicals, Buildings and Grounds, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Includes maintenance brochure mechanicals
    - Mechanicals, Campus Pride, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Includes original art of cartoon people making photocopies, talking on a pay phone, a waitor, pile of books. woman listening to ear phones and writing, standing outside the library
    - Mechanicals, Chris Lombardi, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Includes library images
    - Mechanicals, Maps, 1960-1990s (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Includes map of WCSU situated between Boston and New York, floor plans of various campus buildings, and a map of CT situated between Massachusetts and New York
    - Mechanicals, Colonial Logo, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Includes several versions of the colonial for stationary, sporting events, and general university graphics
    - Mechanicals, Cupola Logo, 1990s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Mechanicals, Western Logos, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Includes mechanicals for brochures: Degree Offerings, Ancell School of Business, and the School of Professional Studies
    - Mechanicals, Project Acorn, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 45.1)
      Project Acorn was a greening of WestConn project conceived by the all-volunteer Center for Urban Studies and supported by the college administration, Alumni Association, and the midtown dorm council. The project called for planting shade trees, evergreens, flowering trees and flower, and installing brick patios, flagstone paths, outside seating arrangements, additional stairs, pathways and ramps around the Ruth A. Haas Library.
    - Mechanicals, Outreach, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      Includes ads and brochure mock-ups for degree offerings, general university promotion, and Ancell School of Business
    - Mechanicals, Awards, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 47)
      Includes recognition, appreciation, honors, participation, award, and honorary degree certificates
    - Mechanicals, Invitations, 1990s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Includes university balls, and holiday parties
    - Mechanicals, Fundraising, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 49)
      Includes Westconn Society
    - Invitations, 1985-2009 (Box 1, Folder 50-52)
      Includes university balls, fundraising dinners, award presentations, Presidential Inaugurations, convocations, retirement dinners, admissions breakfasts, President's lectures, and events
    - Christmas Cards, 1988-2006 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - University Events, 1983-2010 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      Includes open house, accepted student's day, mardi gras, President's lecture, homecoming breakfast, anniversary celebration, meteorology workshop, family weekend, homecoming, photography exhibition, and groundbreaking ceremony
    - Programs, University Centers, 1989-2010 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Includes Jane Goodall training summit, Kenya Chapter One Project, study abroad, honors program, Center for Collaboration, and Sights & Sounds at the Silo
    - Programs, Memorials, 1983-1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Includes Laura Duffy, Jocelyn Ann Joudy, Scott Andrews, Kelly Dery, Ann Marie Romeo, and Anthony V. Ficarra
    - General Outreach Fliers and Brochures, 1979-2000s (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
      Includes Poetry readings, strategic planning seminar, photography exhibition,movie series and "We're in manufacturing, too. We make precision minds."
    - Fall Open House, 1990s-2000s (Box 2, Folder 5.1)
    - Admissions Accepted Students Materials, 1980s-2009 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Includes welcome packet, folders, orientation, and transfer materials
    - Admissions Applications, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Flyers, Fundraising, 1980-2011 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
      Includes Westconn 100, and Westconn Society
    - Human Resources, circa 2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)